A Guide to the Louis O. Kunkel papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA172
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Correspondence, 1930-1959; 3
  - H-Ha
    - Hartman, F.W. Meeting: Detroit, Mich, Henry Ford Hospital, International symposium on the dynamics of virus infection. Paper delivered "Maintenance of yellows-type viruses in plants and insect reservous". Correspondence includes typescripts of discussion (1 with corrections) and preliminary announcement of program, 1953 October 21-23; 8 items (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Meeting: Detroit, Mich, Henry Ford Hospital, International symposium on the dynamics of virus infection. Paper delivered "Maintenance of yellows-type viruses in plants and insect reservous". Correspondence includes typescripts of discussion (1 with corrections) and preliminary announcement of program
    - Hartt, C.E., 4 items (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Harvard University, 1934-1941; 43 items (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Correspondence primarily material as Member of Committee to visit the Division of Biology of Harvard College (Dr. Kunkel member from 1934-1941).
      Includes letters of appointment to Committee from Bd. of Overseers of Harvard College and booklets listing various committee members and addresses for 1934-35, 1935-36, 1936-37, 1937-38, 1940-41. Also includes Correspondence with various committee members.
  - Ha-Hi
    - Haskell, R.J., 2 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Haskins, C.P., 1 item (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Hastings, L., 2 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Hatch, A.B., 17 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Haulenbeek, J.B., 2 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Havis, L., 6 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Hawaiian Sugar Planters' Assoc, 2 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Heald, F.D., 1931 1944; 10 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Hebrew Sheltering and Immigrant Aid Society of America, 2 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Hedgcock, G.G., 2 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Heidrick, L.E., 1 item (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Heinze, K., 6 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Heldt, T.J., 1 item (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Helgeson, E.A., 4 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Helm, C.A., 2 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Helson, G.A.H., 1948 1956; 6 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Henderson, Peter & Co., 3 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Henderson, W.J., 6 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Henry, A.W., 6 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Henry, L.K., 3 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Hensell, F.C., 1 item (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Herelle, F. d', 3 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Herr, J.F., 4 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Herring, L.K., 3 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Hermann & Cie, 2 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Herrmann & Grace Co., 1 item (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Hershey, J.W., 4 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Hess, A.F., 1932 November; 12 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
      Meeting: 17 NY City Academy of Medicine Harvey Society meeting. Harvey lecture "Similarities between diseases of the vegetable kingdom and those of man and animals"
    - Heuberger, J.W., 6 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Hickey, J.J., 2 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
      Comments favoring Eisenhower vs Stevenson as President
    - Higgins, B.B., 3 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Higley, L.A., 2 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Hildebrand, A.A., 2 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Hill, A.J., 2 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Hill, E.G., 1 item (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Hill, R., 1 item (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Hilton, J.C., 2 items (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Hildebrand, E.M. At RIMR 1939-1940, 1933-1957; 160 items (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Professional Correspondence between colleagues socially friendly.
      Includes recommendations for a Guggenheim fellowship and employment.
  - Ho (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Hoffmann, W.H., 2 items (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Hogan, W.D., 1 item (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Hogansville Nurseries, 8 items (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Holaday, K., 2 items (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Holcombe, H.B., 2 items (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Hollowell, E.A., 5 items (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Hlzl, R., 1 item (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Hon, C., 1 item (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Honey, E.E., 7 items (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Honigmann, H.L., 4 items (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Hooker, W.J., 2 items (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Horn, N.L., 8 items (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Horsfall, J.G., 1935 1942 1950; 11 items (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Includes recommendation for Folke Johnson.
    - Hospital office RIMR, 1 item (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Hotels, 20 items (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Indicates confirmations from various hotels for attending meetings
    - Howard, W.L., 2 items (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Howatt, J.L., 2 items (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Howe, M.A., 1 item (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Recommendation for C. Cartright
    - Howell, S.F., 2 items (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Hoyman, W.G., 17 items (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Holmes, F.O., 1932-1949; 35 items (Box 8, Folder 6)
      At RIMR 1932 to emeritus. Brought to RIMR from Boyce-Thompson.
      Includes: Holmes holographs and 1923-1944 bibliography. Meeting: Correspondence indicates Kunkel attends 1944 Dec 9-11 Cincinnati, American Phytopathological Society meeting. Paper delivered "on x-disease of peach and transmission to perwinkles and other herbaceous plants by dodder".
    - Humphrey, H.B. (206) (Editor-in-chief of Phytopathology), 1931-1944 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      Correspondence primarily about submitting papers for publication by Kunkel and others on Dr. Kunkel's staff; reviewing of mss for publication and other workings as member of editorial board. Served as Associate Editor of Phytopathology 1931-1934. Address:.
      Includes Correspondence about 1935 ca. Dec 23 address to council members of The American Phytopathological Society concerning details of certain editorial policies.
  - Hu-Hy (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Huebner, J., 2 items
    - Huffington, J.M., 1951 November 6; 3 items
      Meeting: West Springfield, Mass. American Phytopathological Society meeting. Paper delivered "A review of 40 years of research in the field of plant viruses".
    - Huger, M., 2 items
    - Hughes, J.F. Co., 1 item
    - Hunter, H.B. Co., 3 items
    - Husted, L., 3 items
      Recommendations for J.S. Niederhauser, J.H. Jensen, C.M. Tucker
    - Hutchins, L.M., 1931-1955; 34 items
      Professional Correspondence between colleagues. Includes letter of congratulations upon Hutchins' retirement.
    - Hutchinson, W.G., 1 item
    - Huttleston, D.G., 2 items
    - Hutton, E.M., 2 items
    - Hwang, L., 1 item
    - Hyde, R.R. Address, 1936 January 21; 12 items
      Includes Correspondence about 1936 Jan 21 Baltimore, Md. Johns Hopkins Univ. School of Hygiene and Public Health lecture [title not known].
  - I-In
    - Idaho State Experiment Station, 1 item (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Inman, O.L., 19 items (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Instituto Butantan, 3 items (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Institut fr Pflanzenkrankheiten..., 1 item (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - International Botanical Congress, 6th., 7 items (Box 9, Folder 2)
      Invited to attend and present paper but declines. Includes preliminary program.
    - International Botanical Congress, 7th., 4 items (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - International Botanical Congress, 8th, 3 items (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - International Congress of Biophysics., 3 items (Box 9, Folder 2)
      Invited to present paper but declines. Includes general information with list of participants.
    - International Committee on Description and Nomenclature of Plant Viruses (Originally International Committee on plant virus diseases), 1931-1940; 45 items (Box 9, Folder 3)
      Dr. Kunkel member of this committee.
      Correspondence primarily with J. Johnson on workings of committee and its members.
      Includes typescript of 1939 April "A memorandum of the tentative International system of plant virus nomenclature" with Kunkel letter of congratulations on this ms. (See also under: International Congress for Microbiology, 3rd Box no. 9 and Johnson, James Box no. 9).
    - International Congress for Microbiology, 3rd Meeting: NYC Waldorf-Astoria Hotel., 1939 September 2-9; 42 items (Box 9, Folder 4)
      Dr. Kunkel on executive committee involved in organizing Congress. Also a vice-president of Section III on Viruses and viral disease.
      Paper delivered "Virus mutations". Includes Kunkel recommendations for paper presentation by T. Fukushi and H.H. Storey.
      Includes pamphlet of Congress announcement and typescripts of Kunkel statements made in discussing Smith and McKinney papers. At this meeting Committee on description and nomenclature of plant viruses met jointly with Committee on description and nomenclature of animal viruses for discussion. (See under: International Committee on Description and nomenclature of plant viruses Box no. 9).
    - International Congress for Microbiology, 4th., 4 items (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Invited to attend but declines
    - International Congress for Microbiology, 7th., 2 items (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Invited to attend but declines.
    - International Society for Microbiology., 3 items (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Invited to attend 2nd International Congress for Microbiology but declines
    - Interstate Chemical Mfg. Co., 2 items (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Irons, V., 2 items (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Ivanoff, S.S., 1935-1945; 46 items (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - J-Ju (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Jacob, J.L., 1 item
    - Jacobs, H.L., 2 items
    - Jacobs, W.A., 1 item
    - Jagendorf, A.T., 6 items
    - Jeffers, H.W., 1 item
    - Jenkins, A.E., 1934 1948; 7 items
    - Jenkins, W.A., 2 items
    - Jensen, D.D., 1939 1947; 5 items
    - Jewell, F.F., 1 item
    - Johnson, A.G., 1 item
    - Johnson, B., 3 items
    - Johnson, E.C., 2 items
      Recommendation for Dr. Black.
    - Johnson, E.M., 4 items
    - Johnson, F.H., 4 items
    - Johnson, J.P., 2 items
    - Johnston, J.R., 2 items
    - Johnston, T.H., 1 item
    - Johnstone, D.B., 3 items
    - Johnstone, W.C., 3 items
    - Jonas, H., 2 items
    - Jones, D.F., 2 items
    - Jones, F.R., 4 items
    - Jones, L., 1 item
    - Jones, Leon K., 8 items
    - Jones, Linus H., 13 items
    - Jones, L.R., 1932-1938; 25 items
      Professional Correspondence between colleagues socially friendly. Includes Jones holographs.
    - Jones, S.G., 2 items
    - Jongeneel, L.W., 4 items
    - Jordan, D.C., 1 item
    - Josephson, L.M., 2 items
    - Journal of Biological Chemistry, 1 item
    - Journal of Experimental Medicine, 2 items
    - Journal of Physical Chemistry, 2 items
    - Jucci, C., 1 item
    - Jensen, James H. At RIMR 1931-1935, 1930-1955; 82 items (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Dr. Kunkel representative of the American Phytopathological Society at the Convocation celebrating 75 anniversary of the Experiment Station at Rutgers, 1955 Oct 6.
    - Johnson, Folke. At RIMR 1939-1941, 1939-1950; 45 items (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Includes Johnson biographical material with photograph; college transcript; recommendations for; Johnson holographs.
    - Johnson, James, 1932-1955; 52 items (Box 9, Folder 9)
      Professional Correspondence between colleagues.
      Includes typescript of Johnson ms "The nomenclature of plant viruses" with Kunkel comments on ms. and other comments concerning nomenclature of plant viruses and its committee; recommendations for A.F. Ross. (See also under: International Committee on Description and Nomenclature of Plant Viruses Box No. 9).
  - K-Ku
    - Kadish, M.A., 1 item (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Kaeiser, M., 3 items (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Kahn, R.P., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Kaiser, C., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Kaiser, S., 1934 1943; 5 items (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Kamat, M.N., 3 items (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Kamerling, S., 3 items (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Karling, J.S., 1931 1941; 4 items (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Includes Correspondence about serving as member of the 75 Anniversary celebration committee of the Torrey Botanical Club.
    - Kartman, L., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Kassanis, B., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Katznelson, H., 5 items (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Kausar, A.G., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Kawamura, E., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Keener, P.D., 8 items (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Kehr, A.E., 11 items (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Keitt, G.W., 1934-1950; 17 items (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Professional correspondence between collegues. Includes typescript of Keith and Pryor ms "A destructive bud-transmissible disease of sour cherry in Wisconsin".
    - Keller, D.S., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Kellerman, K.F., 8 items (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Kelley, W.E., 1 item (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Kelman, A., 16 items (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Correspondence primarily about working at RIMR with A.C. Braun for 3 months. Includes Kelman et al reprints.
    - Kemmerer, V.L., 1932; 4 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Address: 1932 Apr 23 White Plains, NY White Plains High School. Presentation "Plant ailments and their similarity to human ailments"
    - KenKnight, G., 6 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Kent, G.C., 3 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Kerridge, J.R., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Recommendation for L.M. Black.
    - Khan, A.M., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Kidd, J.G., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Kiesling, R.L., 1 item (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Kille, E.H., 4 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Kilner, F.R., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Kinetic Chemicals Inc., 6 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - King, C.G., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Recommendations for D.D. Keck and G.S. Avery
    - Kirkwood, E., 1 item (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Kline, J.F., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Klinkowski, M., 13 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Klugman, S., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Knecht, M.A., 5 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Includes recommendations for.
    - Kneebone, L.R., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Knight, C.A. 1940; 1952-1954. At RIMR 1940-1948., 1940 1954; 9 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Knowlton, G.F., 1 item (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Knorr, L.C., 10 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Knudson, L., 3 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Kobel, F., 4 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Koch, L.W., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Koehler, B., 3 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Kojima, H., 1 item (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Kono, M., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Kraybill, H.R., 6 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Kreitlow, K.W. At RIMR 1940-1941, 1940-1947; 36 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Includes biographical material with college transcript; typescripts of abstract of thesis and Kreitlow papers presented at various meetings.
    - Krieger, L.C., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Kunitz, M., 1 item (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Congratulations to Kunitz on becoming Member, RIMR
    - Kunz, E.F., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - L-La (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Lackey, C.F., 2 items
    - Laird, C.N., 1 item
    - Laird, R.L., 6 items
    - Lal, S.B., 1 item
    - Lampton, R.K., 1 item
    - Lancaster, F.R., 2 items
    - Lancaster Press Inc., 2 items
    - Landauer, W., 5 items
    - Landsteiner, K., 2 items
    - Lang, B.J., 2 items
    - Lang, O., 2 items
    - Langer, C.A., 1947 January 14-16; 4 items
      Meeting: East Lansing, Mich. Michigan State College, Fruit Growers' Conference. Paper delivered on Jan 14 on "virus diseases of plants"
    - La Rue, C.D., 2 items
    - Laskaris, T. At RIMR 1941-1946, 23 items
      Includes recommendation for; graduate school transcript.
    - Lathrop, F.H., 2 items
    - Laubenstein, K.G., 3 items
    - Lauffer, M.A. At RIMR 1941-1946, 1937-1958; 35 items
      Includes biographical material with typescript of abstract of Lauffer Ph. D. thesis and recommendation for A.W. Petrie (See also under: Academic Press (Advances in Virus Research Box no. 1).
  - La-Li (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Lauritzen, J.I., 3 items
      Includes typescript of Lauritzen report on Biological Abstracts "Botanical journals and their burden" with Kunkel typescript and Crocker handwritten comments on report.
    - Lavin, G.I., 6 items
    - Lawrence, G.H.M., 6 items
    - Leach, J.G., 1935-1941; 12 items
    - LeClerq, E.L., 1 item
    - Lee, A., 7 items
    - Lefebvre, C.L., 8 items
    - Lehman, S.G., 3 items
    - Lehman, W.E., 3 items
    - Leitz, E. Inc., 1 item
    - Leonard, C.S., 1 item
    - Leonard, S.L., 3 items
    - Leonian, L.H., 4 items
    - Leslie, J.B., 2 items
    - Levene, P.A. Member RIMR, 3 items
    - Lewis, D.E., 10 items
    - Liberty Mutual Insurance Co., 7 items
    - Likhite, V.N., 2 items
    - Lindegren, C.C., 2 items
      Criticism of information cited in a chapter in "The Yeast Cell, Its Genetics and Cytology" by
    - Ling, L., 3 items
    - Link, G.K.K., 1932-1952; 31 items
  - Li-Mc
    - Linn, M.B., 7 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lipman, J.G., 6 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - List, G.M., 3 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Little, R.B. Recommendation for, 1 item (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Liu, K.S., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Livingston, B.E., 1 item (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Livingston, J.E., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Livingston, L.G., 7 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lloyd, F.E., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lochridge, L.P., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Loehwing, W.F., 3 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Recommendation for Wm. H. Lutton Co. as contractors
    - Login, B. & Son Inc., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lohman, M.L., 19 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lang, A., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Long, B., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Look Magazine, 2 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Loomis, NH, 6 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Loring, H.S. At RIMR 1935-1939, 1935-1938 1948; 12 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Includes W.M. Stanley Correspondence recommending H.S. Loring for Eli Lilly award with biographical material and bibliography.
    - Loureiro de, J.A., 5 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lowe, J., 5 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Luck, B., 1 item (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Ludewig, S., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lupinek, B., 1932 1948; 2 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lutton, W.H. Co., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Lyons, J.C., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Ma, R., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - McAllister, R.W., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - MacArthur, C., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - McCallan, S.E.A., 1 item (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - McCallum, L., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - McCarthy, P.J., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - McClean, A.P.D., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - McClintock, J.A., 1931-1948; 9 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - McClintock, M., 1 item (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - McCormick & Co., 1 item (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - McCubbin, W.A., 5 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - McDermott, J.J., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - McEwen, F., 1 item (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - McGinley, J.R., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - McGrew, J., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - MacInnes, D.A., 1 item (Box 10, Folder 6)
      Recommendation for F.F. Flint for APS grant
    - McIntyre, B., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - MacKay, E.M., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - McKinley Publishing Co., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - McKinney, H.H., 1931-1937; 22 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
      Includes exchange of comments on Drs. Chester and Stanley published papers.
    - McKinstry, D.W., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - MacKnight, R.H., 3 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - MacLachlan, J.D., 5 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - McLaughlin, G.D., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - McLean, D.M., 1 item (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - McLean, J.H., 2 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - McLean, R.K., 11 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - MacLeod, D.J., 1936-1953; 19 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - MacLeod, J., 3 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Macnamara, J., 3 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - MacRae, N.A., 3 items (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - McNew, George L. At RIMR 1935-1939, 1935-1953; 88 items (Box 10, Folder 7)
      Professional Correspondence between colleagues socially friendly. On Dr. Kunkel recommendation McNew becomes Director of Boyce - Thompson Institute in 1949.
      Includes evaluation of Armin Braun; McNew et al reprints.
  - Mc-Mar (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - McWhorter, F.P., 1931 1947; 29 items
    - Mai, W.F., 1953; 14 items
      Includes a public lecture and departmental lectures and weekly discussions.
      Lectures: 1953 March (month of) Ithaca, NY Cornell University Department of Plant Pathology. Lecture series on plant viruses
    - Maier, J., 2 items
    - Majoros, M., 2 items
    - Malaguti, G., 2 items
    - Malter, H.E., 2 items
    - Mandenberg, E.C., 6 items
    - Mangelsdorf, A.J., 4 items
    - Mangelsdorf, P.C., 4 items
    - Manns, T.F., 1934-1949; 25 items
    - Maramorosch, K. At RIMR 1949-1961, 1948-1949 1957; 12 items
      Includes recommendation for and biographical material.
    - March of Time, 1 item
    - Marlatt, C.L., 3 items
    - Marple, H.N., 1 item
    - Marquette, W.G., 1931-1932 1949; 6 items
    - Marsh, A.E., 2 items
    - Marsh, G., 2 items
    - Marshak, A., 2 items
    - Martin, G.W., 1 item
    - Martin, J.N., 2 items
  - Mar-Me
    - Martin, J.P., 5 items (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Includes photographs of induced buds arising from stem galls.
    - Martin, W.H., 4 items (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Marucci, P.E. (Box 11, Folder 2)
      See under: Doehlert, C.A. Box no. 6.
    - Mary Camilla S.N.D., Sister, 2 items (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Massachusetts Agricultural Experiment Station, 1 item (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Massey, L.M., 1931-1947; 32 items (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Professional Correspondence between colleagues. Includes recommendation for A.F. Ross and S.S. Cohen.
    - Mathews Construction Co., 2 items (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Mathias, E.J., 2 items (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Matz, J., 9 items (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Mavrodineanu, R., 4 items (Box 11, Folder 2)
      About employment for (a displaced Rumanian) at request of G. Palade.
    - May, C., 1 item (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Mead, F.W., 2 items (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Medford, M., 1 item (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Medler, J.T., 10 items (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Meier, F.C., 1 item (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Melchers, L.E., 12 items (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Melhus, I.E. Professional Correspondence between colleagues, 1931-1956; 39 items (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Professional Correspondence between colleagues. Includes Correspondence reminiscing on visit to Caribou, Maine and congratulations on Melhus 75 birthday; photograph of corn virus disease.
  - Me-Mi (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Menzies, J.D., 1944-1952; 26 items
    - Merrill, E.D., 8 items
      Includes Kunkel statement "Relation of plant sciences to national land utilization planning" and Correspondence describing development and evaluation of Stanley's work on tobacco mosaic disease.
    - Messenger Foundation Lectures, 1942 May 12; 21 items
      Lectures: 1942 May 12 Ithaca, NY Cornell University Messenger lecture. Paper delivered "New hosts as a key to progress in plant virus disease research"
    - Metcalf, Z.P., 6 items
    - Metropolitan Greenhouse Mfg. Corp., 1 item
    - Meyer, Bernard S. (Editor of American Journal of Botany), 12 items
      Review of papers for publication in American Journal of Botany by.
      - Takahasi, U.N. "A respiratory study of virus-infected plant tissues"
      - Bald, J.G. "Additional methods for fixing and staining viruses in infected plant tissues"
      - [Author?] "Synergistic effect of plant growth substances and southern bean mosaic virus"
      - Brakke, M.K., Black, L.M. and Wyckoff, R.W.G. "The sedimentation rate of potatoe yellow-dwarf virus"
    - Meyer, M.J., 2 items
    - Michell, H.F. Co., 5 items
    - Milbrath, D.G., 1931-1948, 1959; 1931-1948; 28 items
      Professional Correspondence between colleagues. Includes recommendation for C.N. Priode.
    - Miller, D., 2 items
      Recommendation for F.J. Weidermann for college admission
    - Miller, E., 2 items
  - Mi-Mu
    - Miller, G.L., 1940-1952; 25 items (Box 11, Folder 5)